So, for the past month, this has been my
main laptop. No desk setup, no monitor,
and no docking system. [music] Recently,
I got a rare opportunity to work with
the laptop brand ASUS, which is super
crazy for me considering ASUS is the
first laptop I've ever owned, and it's
what got me into computers and what made
me study computer science in college,
[music] and so I had to take this
opportunity. They wanted me to try out
their latest, most premium laptop, the
ASUS [music]
ExpertBook Ultra, which is their
top-of-the-line, most premium laptop for
business professionals. It's a super
light and powerful laptop that has
almost no compromises. In addition to
testing out this laptop, they also
wanted to
>> [music]
>> fly me out to Taiwan to their
headquarters and see how they designed
it, how they tested it, and also [music]
to meet some of the team members. They
also invited me to Computex, which is
the largest trade show in Taiwan for
computers, and [music] that was a thing
that I've always wanted to go to, so it
was a super cool opportunity that showed
up. Besides that, I was also traveling a
lot. I was in Italy for 2 weeks just for
fun, and so for the past month, this has
been my main [music] laptop cuz I've not
been home. I only got home yesterday.
So, in this video, I'm going to show you
my experience using this computer. If
you're in the market for a new laptop,
the things I saw in the
behind-the-scenes [music] at their
headquarters, and also how it holds up
in my normal productivity workflow. Even
if you're not [music] looking to
purchase a new laptop right now, I think
it'll be interesting to see what the
most premium laptop has to offer today
and whether or not it can actually
replace a full desk setup. All right,
first, the productivity workflow.
[music]
So, the first thing I did after getting
this laptop was, of course, to install
my most-used apps and [music] to see how
it runs on this device. So, I installed
Obsidian, Firefox, Termius for coding,
LM Studio, Telegram, and Tailscale, of
course, to connect to my server. Even
with all the apps running
simultaneously, I never had a
lag or crash or anything like that.
Everything ran super smoothly, [music]
and that's particularly impressive
considering the fact that this laptop is
incredibly thin and comes in at 0.99 kg.
So, [music] they purposely made it way
under 1 kg. And so, it's pretty
impressive [music] to see that this can
actually hold up in pretty extreme
productivity workflows. This is probably
one of the lightest computers that I
own. And it's only after using this
computer that I started to appreciate
light computers. Especially traveling
over the past month and using this
laptop in cafes, airports, and different
places, I really appreciate the fact
that
>> [music]
>> it's really easy and portable to carry
around. In terms of the ports that are
on this laptop, there are two
Thunderbolt USB-C ports, there's two 10
GB USB-A ports, and there's also an HDMI
port and headphone jack.
>> [music]
>> And I actually appreciate the fact that
they have USB-A ports because even
though USB-C is the new default
standard, there are still a lot of
devices that I have that somehow still
use a USB-A port. Like, for example,
this
light right here that's shining on me
that's still using a USB-A port.
>> [music]
>> And so, I've actually used it a handful
of times to connect to multiple things
like different hard drives. And with the
Thunderbolt port, it's also convenient
because you can just plug it into any
monitor to basically have a full desktop
setup when you are at a workstation. I
was also surprised to see that even
though this is a super light
laptop, they did not cheap out on the
keyboard. The typing experience is very
good and I actually really enjoy typing
with this. Also, the trackpad is nice
and large and I had no issues with using
[music] it. You can tell they really
optimized this laptop for business
professionals. Like, even with the
webcam, there's a mechanical privacy
[music] screen that you can cover up
your webcam. Just completely built in.
So,
>> [music]
>> you don't have to tape your webcams
anymore. Even with the display, it's
especially made so that it can work in
all conditions. If If watch the channel,
then you probably have noticed that I
really like matte displays. I even put
matte screen protectors on my other
devices. But, this computer comes with a
matte display, so it's really nice to
use outdoors. And it even has a special
type of display called tandem OLED
displays, which just means that they
stacked multiple OLED displays on it so
that it can have more brightness and be
more efficient in using the battery. So,
that combined with the matte display
made it so that I had no trouble using
this display under [music]
almost every condition that I tested,
including directly under the sun. A lot
of times, depending where you are and
how you use your computer, it's just
nice to be able to scroll through things
just by using your finger versus having
to use the trackpad. It was pretty nice
to have a touchscreen. I watched a few
movies on this laptop over the past
month, first because of the nice
display, but also because they actually
put in six speakers collaborating with
Dolby Atmos. So, the sound quality from
the speakers itself is actually really
good. It's actually kind of overkill,
especially since I think this laptop is
meant for
people in a work setting. So, most
likely people are going to be using
headphones anyways. So, it was [music]
still nice to see that they put in the
effort to make sure that there were no
compromises on this laptop. But, for me,
one of the most important things when it
comes to a mobile setup
>> [music]
>> is battery life because there's almost
nothing more annoying than having to
find [music] a place to charge your
computer when you're working outside.
That's why most of the time when I
travel, I have to carry around this
really big battery bank. And also,
sometimes in different countries, there
might be different types of plugs. Like
I said earlier, that's probably one of
the biggest things that I look for when
it comes to a mobile workstation [music]
setup. And with this laptop, they've
actually been able to achieve a 26-hour
battery life even [music] in this super
thin and light form factor. I had been
so conditioned in [music] the past using
other laptops that I would assume that
the laptop would not be able to last a
whole day, or I would use laptops
[music] at minimum brightness when it's
not being plugged in. But, with this
laptop, because of the battery that they
put in and the software and hardware
optimizations, you can actually use it
at normal brightness throughout the
whole day and not have to charge [music]
it. In the times I was using over the
past month and using it the entire day,
I never had to charge it within the
whole day. And sometimes if I was
[music] not using it that much, I could
even not charge it for 2 days. So,
usually with a laptop, I would carry my
backpack and have a battery bank or have
different chargers in my [music]
backpack, but once I started using this
laptop, I could just carry around this
laptop by itself with no [music] case
and go to a coffee shop. The actual
battery spec is 70 W hours and you can
recharge it to 50% in just 30 minutes.
So, one of the things I like to set up
on my devices [music] is a local LLM, a
local AI model.
And the reason why I like to do that is
because first it's [music] more secure,
but it's also faster with helping out
with different types of tasks.
And especially with moving around and
traveling, I might not always have an
internet connection, so it's really
convenient to have a local AI model that
can assist me with some [music] tasks or
I can just ask the questions when I'm
trying to look something up without the
internet. So, it has a Intel Core Ultra
X7 series 3 processor and it's
specifically optimized for AI. The main
difference compared to a normal chip is
that it has AI acceleration across the
CPU, GPU, and also the NPU. In my tests,
[music] I was able to run a local 9
billion parameter model with no issues
and it could also run a 27 billion
parameter model, but then it would
[music] start to eat the RAM from the
other programs. So, it's definitely not
going to be able to run a 70 billion
parameter model, but it's still pretty
impressive considering the form factor
and size of this laptop. All right, next
part, behind the [music] scenes at Acer
factory. So, after I used the laptop for
about 3 weeks, they flew me to Taiwan to
check out their headquarters and also to
visit them at Computex and I had a super
cool experience. So, I flew to Taiwan
and after I got settled, they invited me
and two pretty established tech content
creators to go for a tour and workshop
in their headquarters. It was a pretty
surreal experience for me. It's probably
one of the first times that I've
actually been brought out by a brand to
do something like this, [music] and I
was also the only person that wasn't a
full-on tech channel. But, their
headquarters was pretty sick. They had a
massive lobby with a bunch of their
products on display with robots, gaming
stuff, [music] and their unreleased
products as well. They showed us how
they test these laptops in different
conditions. So, they had different
machines for doing drop tests,
temperature tests, water tests, and even
scratch tests.
And it kind of reminded me of my first
job, which was working in a Taiwanese
company doing motherboard testing. And
so, it's kind of cool to see that now
I'm on the other side watching them do
it. But, after that we had this workshop
where we [music] met with the product
managers and designers who made this
laptop, and they talked about the
tradeoffs that they made and how they
were able to pack
>> [music]
>> so much into this small form factor. In
the media room, there was a torn-down
version of this laptop, and they
basically explained and showed us how
there is absolutely zero wasted space,
and they specifically had to even
redesign certain components [music] so
that it could fit into this tiny form
factor and stay under 1 kg. One thing I
asked them about the laptop was I
[music] would notice that there would be
certain scratches on the laptop, like
especially if if you rub your hand over,
there would be like a scratch. Not sure
if you can see it, but it would kind of
go away if you just wiped over it on the
laptop. And I asked [music] them what
sort of material they used for the
laptop. And apparently they use this
nano ceramic material for the laptop,
which is one of the strongest materials
they can use for a device like this. And
to illustrate how strong this material
is, the product manager, they used like
a Sharpie to draw all over the laptop,
and they erased it with no issues, and
she also took a coin and scratched it as
hard as she could on the laptop and
showed that there were no scratches
whatsoever.
So, basically after that, whenever I
carry this laptop, I just would throw it
in a bag and not really have to care
about any scratches. And I don't think
there are any scratches on this laptop
at all. They also had their security
engineering team come out, [music] and
they explained how they actually
engineered this laptop to be the highest
spec [music] possible, which is a
military-grade security. And what that
basically meant is that it's certified
to be in the United States military,
[music] and it's very rare that you can
buy a laptop with that level security in
the consumer market. [music]
So, hearing that, personally, I think
this would be an amazing laptop to run
Linux on, and that's probably what I'll
do if they let me keep this laptop. But
even with Windows, I think this is
probably [music] one of the best
experiences that I've had with using
Windows because
the hardware is just so good on this
laptop. And so, if you're in the market
for a business or professional laptop, I
think this is [music] one of the best
ones that you can find. So, if you're
interested, you can check out the link
in the description. You can get the
ExpertBook Ultra on the ASUS store now.
>> [music]
>> So, yeah, thanks for watching this
video. If you've been watching this
channel for a while, then you know this
is a pretty rare and big opportunity for
the channel. So, if you want to see this
channel keep growing, definitely make
sure to like and subscribe to the
channel so I can make better videos for
you guys. I did prepare this entire
video with the ASUS ExpertBook Ultra,
and yeah, that's the power of Intel
inside the ASUS ExpertBook Ultra,
available on the ASUS
store now. See you in the next video.
Let's get it.
Peace.
>> [music]